[instrumental music]
Hey.
So I'm pulling turf
out of my teeth, right?
We're on our own 8 yard line.
Third and 25.
The crowd's hollering
for our blood, right?
Hey, Doc.
So I look over at the guys
and I say, "gentlemen..."
I believe we got 'em
right where we want 'em
Hey, I wanna get you guys
another round. Right?
Still gotta pay for it,
but I'm gonna get it for you.
- Here you go, Doc.
- Hey, thanks.
Hey. Hey. Just booked
a guest spot Thursday.
Oh.
Who's the greatest
agent in the world?
You are, Alex.
Star quarterback to TV star.
Just wait.
Good man, Jakey.
And you're my biggest fan,
Say, you and I go
talk some business.
Busy, busy, busy.
[indistinct chattering]
[horn blaring]
[man]
Yo, Doc! You're the best!
'Hey, how about an autograph?'
Alex, you seen the big man?
Got a question about
that fan expo in Florida.
Yeah, he's just leaving.
You might catch him.
- Thanks, man.
- Alright, Steve.
[explosion]
[indistinct chattering]
[man #1]
'Did you see anything?'
[man #2]
'No, stay back!'
Oh, Doc!
[intense music]
[siren blaring]
Agent Wainright,
Lisbon's on her way over.
What about Rigsby?
Apparently, doc was killed
with a car bomb.
Rigsby's in San Francisco
for court.
Who's Doc?
I thought you knew.
Our victim's Doc Dugan.
You know, the..
Is that football?
Uh... yeah.
Doc Dugan is dead.
And to make matters
more interesting,
one of our witnesses put
the explosion on YouTube.
- It's gone viral.
- Well, welcome to the future.
They promise us jet packs
they give us
compromised investigations.
Look, I'll, I'll take care of
the media. You guys just go..
...solve the case.
[police radio chatter]
Traffic on the 5, Cho?
You recognize my footsteps.
That's weird.
Van Pelt saw
someone she knew.
She didn't do the "boss is
here" posture check.
Rigsby's away.
Therefore, Cho.
Agent and manager saw
the whole thing.
Agent and manager
for a sports bar owner.
Well, even you know
who Doc Dugan was.
Someone rich and famous
and full of himself,
judging by the ride.
Doc Dugan is
one of two quarterbacks
to throw 50 touchdowns
in a year
and the only one to throw over
3,000 yards in eight seasons.
He's a local boy. Retired two
years ago, opened that bar.
Football star.
He ever win the big game?
2003.
Excuse me.
- You're the agent?
- Manager. Steve Penn.
I'm the agent.
I'm Alex Sodko.
Listen, I think I saw somebody
running away after the blast.
I think I saw him, too.
Did Doc have a place
nearby somewhere
where he could be alone?
He's got an office--
Not an office.
A-a privateplace.
There's a studio apartment
down the block.
He used it as a guesthouse.
Take me there right now.
Alright. This way.
what's this about?
A victim's private places
tell you a lot about 'em.
I gotta hunch we'll find
a better than average lead.
Like what?
Oh, his championship ring,
for starters.
[intense music]
Doc?
What the hell?
Ah, like I said, the ring
for starters.
And, of course,
there's the..
...better than average.
[theme music]
[horn honks]
[man #1]
'Yo, Doc! Come back!
Hey, how about an autograph?'
[explosion]
ohh!
Oh, poor Jakey.
[sighs]
[Lisbon]
You didn't hear the explosion?
Huh? Yeah, I heard it.
I was busy.
[sighs deeply]
I should be dead.
Somebodyis.
Tell us about Jake.
He was Doc's assistant
for the past year or so.
He's a great kid.
I loved that kid.
I-I loved that kid.
I'll never find
another assistant like that.
Why was Jake driving your car
and wearing your jacket?
Oh, I was dodging a subpoena.
Another lawsuit?
You didn't tell us that.
Well, Anna's looking
for more money.
- Who's Anna?
- My ex-wife.
Look, Jake and I look
like each other,
so sometimes I'd have him
go out and cover my trail.
Poor Jake.
[cell phone ringing]
Oh, it's a reporter.
Well, he's about to get
a great scoop.
Doc Dugan lives.
Give that, please. Excuse me.
Thank you. Hello.
[Jane]
'Which paper you with?'
This is Patrick Jane
with the CBI.
[Jane]
'California Bureau
Of Investigation.'
Oh, you heard
Doc Dugan's dead?
[inhales]
Yeah.
Uh really, really dead.
Wicked witch of the west dead.
[Jane]
'Okay. Alright.'
Thank you. I'm sorry. Bye.
What was that?
- I'm not dead.
- Yes, you are.
Think about it.
The people in this room
are the only people that know
he's still alive.
We've never had
a live murder victim before.
- So?
- So embrace it.
How many times during a case we
wished we talk to the victim?
Are you crazy?
What about them?
Well, tell 'em Doc left
and then the bomb went off.
I don't know, Doc. This is, uh,
this is a little out there.
- A little?
- I don't want to play dead.
Do you wanna
catch the killer?
Huh? Do you want
to catch the killer?
Okay, then trust me.
We will run a trick play
they will never see coming.
- Let's do it.
- Splendid.
We'll hide you
in a spare office at the CBI.
Won't Wainright
have a problem with that?
Uh, well, we--we won't tell him.
What he doesn't
know won't hurt him.
Compile a list of friends and
family for Lisbon to interview?
No. No, what about
Jake's next of kin?
Oh, I-I have to tell
his mother.
[Jane]
'No, no, no.
You stay out of sight.'
What do you say, Lisbon?
Huh? What do you say?
Mrs. Stewart, I know it's a lot
to ask but I'm asking.
Will you let us
make it look like
it was Doc that died in the
explosion and not your son?
If you say no,
we won't do it.
Will it help you catch
my son's killer?
I can't promise you that
but that's our hope.
But first,
I have to ask you
do you think
it was possible
that Jake was
the intended victim?
No.
It's impossible that anyone
would want to hurt my son Jake.
Doc, on the other hand--
He had a lot of enemies.
[sighs]
Let me put it to you
this way.
There are only two people
in the world
who really loved Doc Dugan.
One of them was my son.
The other one was Doc himself.
[sighs]
Two days.
You got two days.
And then I intend
to bury my son.
[intense music]
You're the agent
and you're the manager.
There's a difference.
You're the enforcer
and you,
in your jeans and blazer
are the hand holder,
the enabler.
[chuckles]
The enabler. You're pretty good.
Managers are more one-on-one.
I've been with Doc
since the beginning.
You played a little ball.
Yeah. Till my knee took me
out. Then I saw Doc,
college kid with one
of the best arms I've ever seen.
I said I'll take
him to the promised land.
Touching story.
You're the mercenary.
I get things done.
It's been two years
since Doc's been out.
It's time for a comeback.
Steve thinks that having a house
full of signed memorabilia
makes for a pension plan.
Meanwhile, I'm out getting him
endorsement deals, TV deals--
And he's modest, too.
I see.
Agent Lisbon will interview
everyone that ever met Doc
so, uh, let's save her
some time.
Who killed him?
Nobody would want
to hurt doc.
No. Everybody loved him.
Liars, both of you.
But I suppose it's your job.
Close your eyes.
Just close 'em.
Doc's dead.
Who do you think killed him?
On the count of three,
say who. One, two..
three. Who?
- Marie St. Claire.
- Marie St. Claire?
Yeah, doc's girlfriend.
Can't wait to meet her.
- 'Agent Lisbon.'
- Sir.
Doc's agent sent over some
of the threats he'd received.
Some of them jumped out at me.
Uh, "I want to see
Doc taken out back and..."
- Ooh.
- Oh.
"Someone should
rip off his..."
You get the idea.
All signed by "megafan8."
Number 8--
That's Doc's jersey number.
Fan sending hate mail.
I'll get Cho on to it.
Good. Weren't you
just heading upstairs?
No, no. Of course not.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
Make sure you get
enough rest, Agent Lisbon.
- It's good for the brain.
- Yes, sir.
[intense music]
[male commentator on TV]
'An athlete,
a leader, and a champion.'
'The world says good-bye
to one of the greats.'
[knock on door]
I haven't been on television
this much since I retired.
Turns out the best day of your
life's the one after you die.
We've just been going
through your list.
The list of people
who might want to kill you.
You left your ex-wife off.
What's the big whoop?
Typically,
in a murder investigation
detective likes to decide what
is and is not a big whoop.
Fine.
Name's Anna Favreau.
I have her number.
Alright.
Is there anybody else
we should talk to?
Um...
What about Marie St. Claire?
She's on her way in here now.
She's your girlfriend, right?
"Girlfriend" is a word
that I don't like to use.
- Uh, we're friends.
- She lives with you, no?
Sometimes I have her over.
Look, if you want to bring
Marie in, that's fine,
But it's gonna be hard to watch.
Woman's crazy about me.
She'll be heartbroken.
I think I can handle it.
[man on TV]
'There's no doubt that sports..'
How's the trial?
They bumped me till tomorrow
which is fine by me.
You know I hate that stuff.
Sarah has work here, we're
heading to Chinatown
get a little
egg foo yongaction.
She's helping me
prep for the trial.
Cool. So did you see
the lab reports?
- Say again?
- 'The lab reports?'
Oh, yeah, your bomb. Uh, looks
like a pretty standard IED
no exotic parts or chemicals.
Skillful amateur
could have built it.
Gotcha. Thanks.
- Okay. Thanks. You good?
- Yeah.
What's your relationship
with Doc Dugan, Miss St. Claire?
I can't believe he's gone.
He was my rock, you know?
Just my rock.
when was the last time
you spoke to him?
"Her rock."
Your own funeral--
That's when you hear the truth,
what people really think of you.
Woman worships me.
Would you like
to find out why?
No, thanks.
You sure?
Tempting, really, but...
Ishot and killed
my last boyfriend.
I'm not ready
for a relationship yet.
Okay.
Rain check.
Hi.
How long had you
been seeing Doc?
Just before
his marriage went south.
I'm not a home-wrecker.
Anna didn't love him.
Once he wasn't a big
football star, she ignored him
and I didn't.
Marie, Patrick Jane.
Nice to meet you.
What do you think happened
with the diamond pendant?
What diamond pendant?
The $50,000 diamond pendant
Doc charged to his credit card
[Jane]
'six days ago.'
That's lies.
I assumed if you had it,
you'd be wearing it.
Yeah. I knew it.
I knew it.
I knew that son of a bitch
was cheating on me.
I was cheating on her, but
I--there was no diamond pendant.
Self-satisfied bastard acted
like God's gift to women.
News flash--he wasn't.
He was a dumb ex-jock heading
downhill, but you know what?
This is actually all
a blessing because now..
I, can go find a man
who might possibly love me
as much as he loved himself.
Hmm. Marie,
uh, your, uh
lunacy is the lunacy
of an innocent woman.
Unless agent Lisbon
has more questions for you
you're--you're free to go.
- No.
- Oh, and by the way
I don't want you to fret, uh,
over nonexistent jewelry.
There was no diamond pendant.
I made that up just
to make you mad. Carry on.
[Cho]
There you are.
Everybody needs
a little downtime.
That's wisdom
from the mind of Doc Dugan.
I've tracked megafan8
to an online sports forum.
- Looks like he's local.
- Can we get an ID?
I can get a court order,
to reveal the user's info.
There's not enough time.
Jake's mom gave us two days.
Doc's college team
has a game today.
There's a memorial to Doc
during the halftime show.
Megafan8 says
he's gonna live-tweet it.
We get him there,
but how do we find
a single sports freak in
the middle of a football game?
Jane will figure it out.
[Lisbon]
You were suing your ex-husband?
My lawyer thought
he was hiding money from us.
Any idea who might
have killed him?
Nope. Thought about it
myself, but..
you would have, too,
if you'd been married to doc.
- The other women.
- Oh, yeah.
Although I should probably send
that Marie a thank-you card.
Why?
For taking him away from me.
I met Trevor in college,
and he was..
...driven, strong.
You know
how attractive that is.
When the fame and money came,
he handled it all.
Then it ended.
He'd spent his whole life
becoming a star
and never thought
about what came after.
He changed.
He had all these holes
that he'd dug in himself,
and he had to find ways
of filling them.
[Anna]
'That bar.'
Drugs. Other women.
I was sick of it.
Did you kill him?
I didn't kill Trevor,
Agent Lisbon..
but..I don't have a lot
of tears for him, either.
Lisbon's wondering
if I'm making a face at her.
Interesting woman,
your ex-wife.
[Doc]
Yeah, interesting.
I thought hearing
what everybody had to say
about me would be fun.
Truth's rarely fun.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I have your funeral to go to.
[indistinct chattering]
[commentator]
'ordinarily, game day
is a happy occasion.'
'However, this is a tribute
and dedication'
to a very special player.
So at this stadium
where Doc thrilled fans
in his college years
they have gathered
for one last cheer.
Let's find our megafan8,
shall we?
Doc Dugan--
Doc Dugan jersey?
I got football--
Doc Dugan jersey? Come on.
Doc Dugan jersey?
Got footballs, too. $800.
Signed genuine article--
$800 for a football?
Yeah, it's a limited supply.
It's not like Doc's gonna
sign anything else
you may get it
while it's hot.
Matter of fact,
I got a ticket stub
from his last game.
Give me 25 bucks.
Well, that's not signed.
Here, give me this.
- Hey, man. You can't do that.
- "Doc Dugan." there you go.
Whoa. $500.
Tickets for Doc Dugan
signed by theDoc Dugan.
$500 ticket stub.
Anybody...
Megafan8 is here.
He's tweeting that
he's starting to tailgate.
[Jane]
'Okay. Uh, "dear megafan8,'
"you're loudmouthed jerk
"overcompensating
for childhood issues."
we'll start with that
and build.
- Any nibbles?
- No.
Okay, let's dangle
another worm, shall we?
"You talk big on the internet
"because you're
a chicken-stuffed
"loser in
your real life."
"You better shut your mouth
before I shut it for you."
"Move out of
your mother's basement
"and join the real world."
"I'm warning you, dumbass.
Shut up."
Okay, tell him
I'm near gate 4, and, uh,
"if you wanna shut me up
you better put down
your baby blanket and do it."
Yo, yo. Genuine Doc Dugan
t-shirt right here, right here.
Genuine Doc Dugan. $500.
"Bring it, bro."
Say I'm wearing a red
sweatshirt, black baseball cap
with a "J" he can have
the first punch
"that's how pathetic
I think you are."
"Pathetic."
I'm getting worked up.
[Cho]
'And he just went off-line.'
- M-maybe we should get ready.
- For what?
"J" for "jackhole," right?
Hey, you sweatshirt!
I'm talkin' to you.
Oh. Okay, Cho.
I'll show you pathetic.
[grunting]
Get on your stomach.
Gimme your arms.
- Gimme your arms!
- I didn't do anything.
Megafan8, I presume.
Nice entrance.
[crowd cheering]
I don't know why you're
harassing me.I was provoked.
Yeah, we provoked you.
You've said some pretty
rough stuff about Doc.
Why do youcare?
It's not like Imatter.
You threatened a man's life.
Now he's dead. It matters.
[Cho]
'You sure have a lot
of pictures of Doc.'
Doc was my hero.
The way he threw, he moved--
it was perfect.
You're a stalker.
No. I'm a fan.
I was his biggest fan.
And I wanted him
to understand that. That's it.
I went to that bar
and he said, "not now, kid."
"kid."
And that was it.
I own a ball he signed
from the 2004 conference finals.
It cost me 2 grand!
"Not now, kid."
So I wrote the e-mails.
You know this man?
[Megafan8]
'No. Who's that?'
Arnold Green, local luminary
of organized crime.
So what? People come up to me
and shake my hand every day.
Stalkers make good detectives.
It turns out your
number one fan had an alibi
[Lisbon]
'so it's lucky for him.'
Green's been connected with
illegal gambling, point shaving.
Alright, so..
I knew him, but just for hanging
out, is all not gambling.
[chuckles]
I'm sorry. Terrible liar.
Alright, I made a few bets
with him, but never on football.
Huge lie.
Never on my own team.
Okay, but no point shaving
and no games thrown.
I bet to win, I played to win,
every time.
How much better
does that feel, huh?
Get that big secret
out there?
Why wouldn't you
just tell us that, Doc?
Look, if I sign something,
it's worth a lot of money.
My manager, Steve, has
a roomful of the stuff.
How much is my autograph
gonna be worth if this gets out?
I laid some bets with Green,
but when I retired, I quit.
That was it.
[Teresa]
'But Green had other plans.'
No. Not green.
'This guy.'
Martin.
Tough guy.
See that bracelet he's wearing?
That's the bullet that punctured
his lung. This is a bad dude.
What did Martin do?
He demanded I buy
Green's liquor for my bar.
It was way overpriced.
I told him to take off.
You told off a mobster.
Somebody tried to kill you,
and you don't even mention it?
You're as helpful as
an actual murder victim.
Hey, these are tough guys
but they're not gonna hurt
Doc Dugan. We're friends.
- Kinda.
- Right.
Alex and Steve said they saw
somebody feeling the scene.
It could've been
one of Green's guys.
Maybe we should bring Doc Dugan
back from the dead
'wire him up, and then listen
to a conversation with Green.'
- A wire?
- Oh, I got a better idea.
Maybe we need
the other end of the wire
the listening device.
Could come in handy.
'Okay.'
[clearing throat]
Okay. Who has Chinese food
for breakfast?
Chinese people.
And me.
Okay.
Interrogation time.
Agent Rigsby
do you consider yourself
an expert on motorcycle gangs?
- I guess.
- No, don't say, "I guess."
Say, "Yes."
You want to project confidence.
Yes, ma'am.
- Aw.
- Mm.
Don't try to distract me.
And does this expertise
come from years
of close contact
with criminal elements
in your own family?
- Hey.
- Don't say, "Hey."
- Just answer the question.
- No. It doesn't.
Isn't it true that
your father, Steven Rigsby
was a member of
the Iron Gods motorcycle gang?
Yes.
So wouldn't it
be fair to say
everything you learned, you know
from your father, the felon?
[sighs]
Babe, I know it's touchy
but if you wait too long--
I think that's enough.
Thanks.
- It's time to get to court.
- Wayne.
Seriously, it was a big help.
Thank you.
[scoffs]
[man clearing throat]
[indistinct chattering]
Arnold Green?
Oh, that's
a great-looking suit
for a policeman.
Most of you have no taste.
I'm not a policeman.
- She is.
- Yes.
I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
This is Patrick Jane.
Would you like a drink?
We're here to talk to you
about Doc Dugan's death.
- We know you know him.
- Oh, this is official. Okay.
Well, my attorney's name is
Don Hendricks. Give him a call.
You wanted Doc to start
buying liquor from you.
I'm a liquor distributor.
Maybe Doc didn't want to.
You didn't like that.
Did you try blackmailing him?
When that didn't work--
Okay, let's just say
that I'm this scary guy
that you imagine me to be.
You think I couldn't
put the fear
'into some
puffed-up pretty boy?'
If I wanted him to buy,
he was going to buy.
Why should I kill him?
He's worth more to me
alive than dead.
Excellent point. Thank you.
Really helpful.
Lisbon, we can go.
We have what we need.
Next time, call my attorney.
Oh, one more thing.
- Arrest this man.
- For what?
- I don't know. For questioning.
- That's not arresting.
Sir, we're gonna call you
for questioning.
I got nothing to say.
I'm sure we can think
of something to talk about.
[clicking]
[muttering]
We're getting set up
for Martin. You ready?
Almost. I think I might need
some more CBI stationary.
Yeah. Oh.
That's a good--
Hey, I was drinking that.
Oh, sorry. Works very well.
Look at that.
Aging. Very authentic.
Very authentic.
I love arts and crafts.
It really relaxes me.
Just a little more
of that.
[exhales deeply]
Rigsby. Ah.
Uh, welcome back.
Yes.
Is that Katy Perry
over there?
[camera shutter clicking]
Nice.
Uh, don't smile.
What's the capital
of Idaho?
- Uh..
- Quick, quick, quick.
Uh, Boise?
Bingo.
Time to raise the dead.
Oh. Let that paper dry.
It's very important. Thank you.
What's going on here?
You good cop
or the bad cop?
Oh, I'm not a cop.
I'm a psychic.
Sure you are.
We have Doc Dugan with us.
He's kind of mad at you.
Doc Dugan is here?
Mm-hmm.
Yes, right there
in that chair.
I'm locked in here
with a loon.
Wait till my lawyer hears
about this one.
Nice bracelet.
It's the bullet
that didn't kill you, right?
- How do you know about that?
- Doc told me.
The hell he did.
You're a fruitcake,
aren't you?
Ask him a question.
We had lunch once at this place,
some red tablecloth joint.
What'd I order?
Steak. Bloody.
Yeah, big deal.
Well, it's your question.
Ask a harder one.
[sighs]
[Martin]
'Who was playing
at the restaurant?'
[Doc]
'It was Motown.'
Motown.
Always a great choice.
Or a good guess.
Last time we were together,
what'd I say to him?
Um..
uh, change the subject.
Doc doesn't want
to talk about that.
It unsettles his spirit.
Yeah, I knew
you were full of it.
Alright, let's do it.
He came to see me.
He was wearing
a gray leather jacket
black t-shirt, some kind of
lizard skin cowboy boots.
You wore a gray leather jacket,
a black t-shirt
and lizard skin
cowboy boots.
Crocodile boots, yeah.
How'd you know that?
You spoke
with a gravelly voice
like you had a cold
or a flu or something.
He took out his knife
and he..
...held it against my throat.
You held a knife
to his throat.
He started to cry.
You laughed at him.
Called him a girlie-man.
And.
I said
"Don't cut my face, please."
He said,
He's really here.
Doc. Doc, you here?
[clattering]
Look, I'm sorry, man.
I'm sorry, Doc, okay?
Calm down, Doc.
Tell us everything you know
about Doc, Green, extortion
car bombs. It's the only way
to make it stop.
Just get him out of here, okay?
You know what
you have to do.
I know what to do.
I'll talk!
- Just get him outta here!
- Good.
Martin confessed to extortion,
ratted out his boss as well.
So Green's going down.
Great job, buddy.
But did they kill Jake?
Martin claims he had nothing
to do with the car bomb.
He said there were
some very dangerous men
'at the club Green owns.'
Now one of them
is Louis "Louie Boom" Corrado.
We've got a big file on him.
He's been implicated
in almost a dozen murders
all of them bombings.
That sounds promising.
Can I just--
You said you saw
a guy fleeing the scene.
Bring in Louie
for a line-up.
You see his picture,
it taints the ID.
Can I go with you?
Put a SWAT helmet
on me or somethin'?
Sorry. Jane's got
other plans for you.
[door opening]
[telephone ringing in distance]
[groaning]
[container cap clicking]
[pills rattling]
[chuckling]
Does Jane know
you're on his couch?
You hurt your back again?
[sighs]
I'll be fine.
Oh, yeah.
What'd you do?
[sighs]
Tackled a suspect.
You shouldn't tackle people
with you back like that.
[sighs]
Thanks.
We're gonna go
raid the vespers.
Lisbon says to stay here,
man the phones, okay?
Okay.
San Francisco
kind of sucked.
Mm-hmm.
I asked Sarah to help
prep my testimony.
It turned into a fight.
Iturned it into a fight.
She brought up my dad.
Right.
She just goes straight
for the jugular.
She's tough, you know?
She doesn't
look it, but..
When she brings it,
she's as tough as any of us.
You should see
her in court.
She's tearing up a witness,
just really goes to town on 'em.
It's pretty awesome.
'She was doing exactly
what I asked her do.'
I got mad 'cause
she was doing it so well.
I'm such an idiot.
Thanks for listening.
[snoring]
Mr. Green. Nice of you
to show up. You're under arrest.
This is harassment.
No, it's a raid. Your friend,
Martin, turned over a new leaf.
You were under it.
Ron, cuff him.
Hey, boss.
We arresting the bartender?
Why not?
The more, the merrier.
[door opening]
Coast is clear.
Come on.
Where are we heading?
To solve the case.
Didn't we just do that?
Come on, man.
I'm getting so tired of this.
I found out
my relationship is a sham
all my friends
think I'm a punk.
Now you got somebody else who
wants to dump on Doc Dugan.
Truth hurts, I know.
It's biologically-based,
actually.
Our brains process sound
faster than they do light
but light moves
faster than sound.
So our brains are
constantly shifting reality
so the world syncs up.
So?
Only when someone is
standing 30 yards away
do we see and hear the world
exactly as it is.
That's when your brain,
sound, and light
are all in perfect harmony.
The rest of the time,
we're living in a world of lies.
Lies are what make
the world make sense.
Ergo, the truth hurts.
No, no, no, not Anna.
No, no. Nah-nah. No way.
- Have a seat.
- 'Not again.'
I can't.
I know, but sit.
My name is Patrick Jane.
I saw your interview
with Agent Lisbon.
Interesting stuff.
[Anna]
'Is there a problem?'
Yes, there is.
The problem is
you were telling a lie.
Is this about my alibi?
'cause I can--
Nothing to do
with your alibi.
You said you hated
your ex-husband
'but clearly that's
not the case.'
Hey. Here's the file
on the mob bomber, Louie Boom.
Lisbon says give it a read
before we bring him in.
Alex, would you
come with me, please?
[door opening]
We need to go over
your statement.
Oh, yeah, sure.
You don't even know me.
I could see through
half an inch of glass.
You're deeply in love
with your dead ex-husband.
What business is it
of yours?
Just tell me the truth.
Just say the truth.
Fine. You're right.
I loved him.
Somewhere deep down in him was
the good man I used to know.
It got lost when
he retired, but..
he would have found
his way back.
I know he would have.
And now I'll never
see him again
'and I'll never
get to tell him.'
Okay.
Well, that should do it.
Hey, wait.
- Leave her alone.
- Okay.
- Trevor?
- Annie.
What, what are you..
- They said, I thought..
- A trick.
To catch the killer.
I just blew it.
What?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry
about everything.
[groaning]
The guys from vespers
are downstairs.
- Did he go for it?
- Yep.
- Did he go for what?
- Sir.
[indistinct chattering]
Doc Dugan is still alive?
Yes, sir.
'It was his assistant,
Jake Stewart, that died.'
And you chose to hide
this fact from me.
From everyone, for the sake
of the investigation.
- A trick.
- I wouldn't call it a trick.
- Did this work?
- It's still in progress.
Okay, well, um..
Let's hope it turns out
positively, huh?
Yes, sir.
Do you think he would mind
if I got an autograph?
Just a..
Yeah. I'll just..
You know, give them a second.
Good idea, sir.
Any one of these guys
looks like the man you saw
running from the explosion?
You mean Louie Boom.
I mean the man you saw.
I can' tell you
which one is Louie.
It'll taint the lineup.
That's him. Number four.
That's the guy
from the parking lot.
You're sure?
That's Louie?
That's the guy.
Rigsby, come on in.
- Hey, guys.
- He saw me.
- Can he do that?
- We're all friends.
What's going on here?
I'm special Agent Rigsby.
Oh, then, I must have
made a mistake.
You wanted to ace
the test
so you took a little peek.
I made the test.
I made the whole thing up.
There is no "Louie Boom."
[Teresa]
'We gave you a chance
to look, and you took it.'
You said Martin talked.
He said there was no way
Green was behind Doc's death.
Lot of people
didn't like Doc
but most of them made
more money if Doc was alive.
Only Steve here made
more money with Doc dead.
You have a house filled
with memorabilia signed by Doc.
He dies, the prices
go through the roof.
You make a fortune.
Come on.
I saw somebody running away.
- It was an explosion.
- People run from explosions.
Your prints on that file
should be enough
to get a search warrant.
Let's have a look.
The truth
shall set us free.
Well, maybe not all of us.
Where am I going?
Booking, for the murder
of Jacob Stewart
and the attempted murder
of Trevor Dugan.
We found bomb residue
in your garage
and research
in your web history.
Add that to the fact that you
tried to frame Louie Boom.
Hey!
There's a roomful of it
back at your place.
'Stuff signed by me'
packaged to sell
after I'm dead.
I thought we were
friends, Steve.
Friends?
Friends 'cause I get
your coffee?
Because I cover up
every mess you make?
Hide your girlfriend
from your wife?
What'd you ever do for me?
Gave you a job, man.
I was the number one
draft pick.
It should be me
wearing that damn ring.
Youshould beworking for me!
So you built a bomb and you
stuck it on Doug's car.
I just wanted what
was coming to me.
I never meant for Jake to die.
He was a good kid.
Alright, that's enough.
Take him away.
Let's go.
Let me get that.
[door closing]
Wanna take a seat?
Look, I, uh..
I wanted to say I'm sorry
about yesterday.
It's just.. Well, you called me
a dirty cop, Sarah.
Oh, God, I would
never call you that.
I was trying to prepare
you for the defense lawyer.
Yeah, I know.
Thank you.
The trial was
a breeze compared to you.
- Oh, you did good?
- Yeah.
I know you can't help it.
You're a defense attorney.
What's that supposed
to mean?
Oh, come on. You guys
protect criminals for money.
Is that what you
think we do?
Tell me, what is it
exactly that cops do?
We put the bad guys away
if we can get around you.
Sometimes you put
away good guys.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
We have to deal
with cops every day
who can't even
spell "Miranda."
I'm gonna do whatever
I can for my client.
Now do you have
a problem with that?
No.
No problem at all.
Mmm.
[both moaning]
We got him, Mrs. Stewart,
thanks to your help.
No, you're the one
that deserves the thanks.
Doc, too.
'He was really useful.'
I'd like to pay
for Jake's funeral if I can.
Anything else you need.
Thank you, but I don't need
handouts, Mr. Dugan.
Call me Trevor, please,
and it's not a handout.
It's what I owe Jake.
Alright, then.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'd like to stay
a little longer if I can.
Sure.
Again, I am so sorry
for your loss.
[door opening]
I was hoping we could
talk a little bit more
about Jake.
Sure.
I hear he was one hell
of a ballplayer himself.
Yeah, he won the state
championship.
- Senior year, yeah.
- No.
Hey.
All good?
Yeah. Doc seems like
a changed man.
He's had a perspective
few of us ever get.
Energizing, I expect.
Would you want that?
To hear what people say
about you when you're dead?
When I'm dead, they can
burn me in effigy
or build a statue or forget
about me completely.
- I couldn't care less.
- You don't mean that.
Everybody wants
to be remembered.
- Childish vanity.
- I want to be remembered.
You shall be, fondly,
but you won't care about it
because when you're dead,
you're dead,
and until then
there's ice cream.
[silverware clattering]
Mmmm.